Finding Aid for the The Papers of James Hampton Kirkland
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Family Correspondence
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1895 (Box 29, File 16)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1895 (Box 29, File 17)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1895 (Box 29, File 18)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1896 (Box 29, File 19)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1896 (Box 29, File 20)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1897 (Box 29, File 21)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1898 (Box 29, File 22)
- Family Correspondence
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1898 (Box 30, File 1)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1898 (Box 30, File 2)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1899 (Box 30, File 3)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1899 (Box 30, File 4)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1899 (Box 30, File 5)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1900 (Box 30, File 6)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1901 (Box 30, File 7)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1901 (Box 30, File 8)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1902 (Box 30, File 9)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1902 (Box 30, File 10)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1904 (Box 30, File 11)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1905 (Box 30, File 12)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1905 (Box 30, File 13)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1906 (Box 30, File 14)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1907 (Box 30, File 15)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1908 (Box 30, File 16)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1909 (Box 30, File 17)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1910 (Box 30, File 18)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1911 (Box 30, File 19)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1914 (Box 30, File 20)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1915 (Box 30, File 21)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1916 (Box 30, File 22)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1918 (Box 30, File 23)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1919 (Box 30, File 24)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1920 (Box 30, File 25)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1921 (Box 30, File 26)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1922 (Box 30, File 27)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1924 (Box 30, File 28)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1925 (Box 30, File 29)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1926 (Box 30, File 30)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1927 (Box 30, File 31)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1928 (Box 30, File 32)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1929 (Box 30, File 33)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1930 (Box 30, File 34)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1932 (Box 30, File 35)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1933 (Box 30, File 36)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1934 (Box 30, File 37)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1935 (Box 30, File 38)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1938 (Box 30, File 39)
- Family Correspondence
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1939 (Box 31, File 1)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, Undated (Box 31, File 2)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, Undated (Box 31, File 3)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, Undated (Box 31, File 4)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to her grandmother, 1883 - 1885 (Box 31, File 5)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to her grandmother, 1887 - 1888 (Box 31, File 6)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to her father (W. A. Henderson), 1884 - 1887 (Box 31, File 7)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to her father (W. A. Henderson), 1888 - 1903 (Box 31, File 8)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to her mother, 1881 - 1886 (Box 31, File 9)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to her mother, 1887 - 1903 (Box 31, File 10)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to her parents (Mr. and Mrs. W.A. Henderson), Undated (Box 31, File 11)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to her sister (Annie Henderson), 1884 (Box 31, File 12)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to her sister (Annie Henderson), 1885 - 1892 (Box 31, File 13)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to her sister (Annie Henderson), 1903 (Box 31, File 14)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to her sister (Annie Henderson), Undated (Box 31, File 15)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to her daughter (Elizabeth Kirkland), 1918 - 1926 (Box 31, File 16)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to her daughter (Elizabeth Kirkland), 1927 (Box 31, File 17)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to her daughter (Elizabeth Kirkland), 1927 (Box 31, File 18)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to her daughter (Elizabeth Kirkland), 1928 - 1932 (Box 31, File 19)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to her daughter (Elizabeth Kirkland), 1933 - 1934 (Box 31, File 20)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to her daughter (Elizabeth Kirkland), 1935 (Box 31, File 21)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to her daughter (Elizabeth Kirkland), 1936 - 1946 (Box 31, File 22)
- Family Correspondence
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to her daughter (Elizabeth Kirkland), Undated (Box 32, File 1)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to her daughter (Elizabeth Kirkland), Undated (Box 32, File 2)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland to O.C. Carmichael, 1939 - 1941 (Box 32, File 3)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland miscellaneous outgoing, 1887 - 1940 (Box 32, File 4)
  - W. A. Henderson to James H. Kirkland, 1895 - 1920 (Box 32, File 5)
  - W. A. Henderson to Mary Henderson Kirkland, 1896 (Box 32, File 6)
  - W. A. Henderson to Mary Henderson Kirkland, 1897 (Box 32, File 7)
  - W. A. Henderson to Mary Henderson Kirkland, 1898 (Box 32, File 8)
  - W. A. Henderson to Mary Henderson Kirkland, 1899 (Box 32, File 9)
  - W. A. Henderson to Mary Henderson Kirkland, 1900 (Box 32, File 10)
  - W. A. Henderson to Mary Henderson Kirkland, 1901 (Box 32, File 11)
  - W. A. Henderson to Mary Henderson Kirkland, 1902 (Box 32, File 12)
  - W. A. Henderson to Mary Henderson Kirkland, 1902 (Box 32, File 13)
  - W. A. Henderson to Mary Henderson Kirkland, 1903 - 1905 (Box 32, File 14)
  - W. A. Henderson to Mary Henderson Kirkland, 1906 - 1907 (Box 32, File 15)
  - W. A. Henderson to Mary Henderson Kirkland, 1908 - 1911 (Box 32, File 16)
  - W. A. Henderson to Mary Henderson Kirkland, 1913 - 1914 (Box 32, File 17)
  - W. A. Henderson to Mary Henderson Kirkland, 1915 - 1916 (Box 32, File 18)
  - W. A. Henderson to Mary Henderson Kirkland, Undated (Box 32, File 19)
- Family Correspondence
  - Mrs. W. A. Henderson to Mary Henderson Kirkland, 1896 - 1897 (Box 33, File 1)
  - Mrs. W. A. Henderson to Mary Henderson Kirkland, 1898 - 1999 (Box 33, File 2)
  - Mrs. W. A. Henderson to Mary Henderson Kirkland, 1900 - 1902 (Box 33, File 3)
  - Mrs. W. A. Henderson to Mary Henderson Kirkland, 1904 - 1914 (Box 33, File 4)
  - Mrs. W. A. Henderson to Mary Henderson Kirkland, Undated (Box 33, File 5)
  - Annie Henderson to Mary Henderson Kirkland, 1893 - 1896 (Box 33, File 6)
  - Annie Henderson to Mary Henderson Kirkland, 1896 (Box 33, File 7)
  - Annie Henderson to Mary Henderson Kirkland, 1896 (Box 33, File 8)
  - Annie Henderson to Mary Henderson Kirkland, 1897 (Box 33, File 9)
  - Annie Henderson to Mary Henderson Kirkland, 1897 (Box 33, File 10)
  - Annie Henderson to Mary Henderson Kirkland, 1898 (Box 33, File 11)
  - Annie Henderson to Mary Henderson Kirkland, 1898 (Box 33, File 12)
  - Annie Henderson to Mary Henderson Kirkland, 1898 (Box 33, File 13)
  - Annie Henderson to Mary Henderson Kirkland, 1899 (Box 33, File 14)
  - Annie Henderson to Mary Henderson Kirkland, 1900 (Box 33, File 15)
  - Annie Henderson to Mary Henderson Kirkland, 1900 (Box 33, File 16)
  - Annie Henderson to Mary Henderson Kirkland, 1900 (Box 33, File 17)
  - Annie Henderson to Mary Henderson Kirkland, 1900 (Box 33, File 18)
  - Annie Henderson to Mary Henderson Kirkland, 1901 (Box 33, File 19)
  - Annie Henderson to Mary Henderson Kirkland, 1901 (Box 33, File 20)
- Family Correspondence
  - Annie Henderson to Mary Henderson Kirkland, 1901 (Box 34, File 1)
  - Annie Henderson to Mary Henderson Kirkland, 1902 (Box 34, File 2)
  - Annie Henderson to Mary Henderson Kirkland, 1903 - 1905 (Box 34, File 3)
  - Annie Henderson to Mary Henderson Kirkland, 1906 - 1907 (Box 34, File 4)
  - Annie Henderson to Mary Henderson Kirkland, 1908 (Box 34, File 5)
  - Annie Henderson to Mary Henderson Kirkland, 1908 (Box 34, File 6)
  - Annie Henderson to Mary Henderson Kirkland, 1909 (Box 34, File 7)
  - Annie Henderson to Mary Henderson Kirkland, 1909 (Box 34, File 8)
  - Annie Henderson to Mary Henderson Kirkland, 1910 - 1915 (Box 34, File 9)
  - Annie Henderson to Mary Henderson Kirkland, 1934 - 1939 (Box 34, File 10)
  - Annie Henderson to Mary Henderson Kirkland, Undated (Box 34, File 11)
  - Annie Henderson to Mary Henderson Kirkland, Undated (Box 34, File 12)
  - Annie Henderson to Mary Henderson Kirkland, Undated (Box 34, File 13)
  - Annie Henderson to Mary Henderson Kirkland, Undated (Box 34, File 14)
  - Annie Henderson to W. A. Henderson, 1897 - 1906 (Box 34, File 15)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland incoming Correspondence Abbott - Buttrick (Box 34, File 16)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland incoming Correspondence Capps - Cummings (Box 34, File 17)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland incoming Correspondence Daniel - Ewing (Box 34, File 18)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland incoming Correspondence Flexner - Gray (Box 34, File 19)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland incoming Correspondence Hamblin - Jack (Box 34, File 20)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland incoming Correspondence Jones - Kreuger (Box 34, File 21)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland incoming Correspondence Letton - Marioee (Box 34, File 22)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland incoming Correspondence Mims - Peckham (Box 34, File 23)
- Family Correspondence
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland Incoming Correspondence Pharr - Reynolds (Box 35, File 1)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland Incoming Correspondence Roberts - Snyder (Box 35, File 2)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland Incoming Correspondence Stevenson - Wiley (Box 35, File 3)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland Incoming Correspondence Wilkes - Williamson (Box 35, File 4)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland Incoming Correspondence Wilson - Workman (Box 35, File 5)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland Incoming Correspondence Unknown (Box 35, File 6)
  - Mary Henderson Kirkland Incoming Correspondence Unknown (Box 35, File 7)
  - Elizabeth Kirkland to her parents and grandparents, Undated (Box 35, File 8)
  - Elizabeth Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1906 - 1914 (Box 35, File 9)
  - Elizabeth Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1915 - 1939 (Box 35, File 10)
  - Elizabeth Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, Undated (Box 35, File 11)
  - Elizabeth Kirkland to Mary Henderson Kirkland, 1906 - 1913 (Box 35, File 12)
  - Elizabeth Kirkland to Mary Henderson Kirkland, 1914 (Box 35, File 13)
  - Elizabeth Kirkland to Mary Henderson Kirkland, 1914 - 1934 (Box 35, File 14)
  - Elizabeth Kirkland to Mary Henderson Kirkland, 1936 - 1953 (Box 35, File 15)
  - Elizabeth Kirkland to Mary Henderson Kirkland, Undated (Box 35, File 16)
  - Elizabeth Kirkland to her husband (B. D. Meritt) 1924, 1931 (Box 35, File 17)
  - Elizabeth Kirkland to her son (Arthur Meritt), 1947 (Box 35, File 18)
  - Elizabeth Kirkland to Harvie Branscomb, 1951 (Box 35, File 19)
  - Elizabeth Kirkland to Mr. Taft, 1909 (Box 35, File 20)
  - B. D. Merritt to James H. Kirkland, 1923 - 1938 (Box 35, File 21)
  - B. D. Merritt to Mary Henderson Kirkland, 1926 - 1936 (Box 35, File 22)
  - B. D. Merritt to wife (Elizabeth Kirkland), 1923 - 1944 (Box 35, File 23)
  - B. D. Merritt to son (Arthur Meritt), 1947 (Box 35, File 24)
  - B. D. Merritt to O. C. Carmichael, 1939 (Box 35, File 25)
- Family Correspondence
  - Elizabeth Kirkland Incoming Correspondence Adossicles - Henlen (Box 36, File 1)
  - Elizabeth Kirkland Incoming Correspondence Henderson (Box 36, File 2)
  - Elizabeth Kirkland Incoming Correspondence Houston - Louis (Box 36, File 3)
  - Elizabeth Kirkland Incoming Correspondence McDaniel - McGill (Box 36, File 4)
  - Elizabeth Kirkland Incoming Correspondence Meritt (Box 36, File 5)
  - Elizabeth Kirkland Incoming Correspondence Mims - Ragsdale (Box 36, File 6)
  - Elizabeth Kirkland Incoming Correspondence Robb - Wright (Box 36, File 7)
  - B. D. Meritt Incoming Correspondence Allison - Pattinger (Box 36, File 8)
  - B. D. Meritt Incoming Correspondence, Undated (Box 36, File 9)
  - B. D. Meritt Incoming Correspondence, Undated (Box 36, File 10)
  - Virginia L. Galluchat Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1878 - 1879 (Box 36, File 11)
  - Virginia L. Galluchat Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1883 - 1884 (Box 36, File 12)
  - Virginia L. Galluchat Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1885 (Box 36, File 13)
  - Virginia L. Galluchat Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1886 (Box 36, File 14)
  - Virginia L. Galluchat Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1887 - 1888 (Box 36, File 15)
  - Virginia L. Galluchat Kirkland to G. A. Kirkland, 1862 - 1879 (Box 36, File 16)
  - Virginia L. Galluchat Kirkland to G. A. Kirkland, 1885 (Box 36, File 17)
  - Virginia L. Galluchat Kirkland to G. A. Kirkland, 1885 (Box 36, File 18)
  - Virginia L. Galluchat Kirkland to G. A. Kirkland, 1886 (Box 36, File 19)
  - Virginia L. Galluchat Kirkland to G. A. Kirkland, 1887 - 1888 (Box 36, File 20)
  - Virginia L. Galluchat Kirkland to William Kirkland, 1862 (Box 36, File 21)
  - Virginia L. Galluchat Kirkland to friend, 1887 (Box 36, File 22)
  - Virginia L. Galluchat Kirkland Incoming Correspondence, 1875 - 1886 (Box 36, File 23)
  - G. A. Kirkland to James H. Kirkland, 1868 - 1893 (Box 36, File 24)
  - G. A. Kirkland to Virginia L. Galluchat Kirkland, 1863 - 1886 (Box 36, File 25)
  - G. A. Kirkland to W. D. Kirkland, 1890 (Box 36, File 26)
  - G. A. Kirkland Incoming Correspondence, 1890 - 1891 (Box 36, File 27)
  - W. D. Kirkland (brother) to James H. Kirkland, 1885 - 1893 (Box 36, File 28)
  - W. D. Kirkland (brother) Incoming Correspondence, 1891 (Box 36, File 29)
  - Joseph Kirkland (brother) to G. A. Kirkland, 1863 (Box 36, File 30)
  - William Kirkland (brother) to G. A. Kirkland, 1863 (Box 36, File 31)
- Family Correspondence
  - Sue F. Tarboux (sister) to James H. Kirkland, 1888 - 1895 (Box 37, File 1)
  - Sue F. Tarboux (sister) to James H. Kirkland, 1901 - 1910 (Box 37, File 2)
  - Sue F. Tarboux to Virginia L. Galluchat Kirkland, 1886 (Box 37, File 3)
  - Sue F. Tarboux to G.A. Kirkland, 1879 - 1891 (Box 37, File 4)
  - William Clark Kirkland (father) to G. A. Kirkland, 1863 (Box 37, File 5)
  - Joseph Galluchat (JHK maternal great-grandfather) to his wife Virginia Lawson Galluchat), 1821 (Box 37, File 6)
  - Joseph Galluchat (JHK maternal great-grandfather) to his son (Joseph Galluchat,Jr.), 1821 (Box 37, File 7)
  - Joseph Galluchat Jr. to sister (Virginia L. Galluchat Kirkland) 1879 Joseph Galluchat Jr. to James H. Kirkland, 1876 (Box 37, File 8)
  - James H. Kirkland Incoming Correspondence from family Burnett - Kirkland (Box 37, File 9)
  - James H. Kirkland Incoming Correspondence from family Louise - Orvin (Box 37, File 10)
  - James H. Kirkland Incoming Correspondence from family Sallie - Wilkinson (Box 37, File 11)
  - W. A. Henderson Outgoing Correspondence, 1906 - 1907 (Box 37, File 12)
  - W. A. Henderson Incoming Correspondence (Box 37, File 13)
  - Mrs. W. A. Henderson Outgoing Correspondence, 1902 (Box 37, File 14)
  - Mrs. W. A. Henderson Incoming Correspondence (Box 37, File 15)
  - Arthur H. Meritt to mother (Elizabeth Kirkland ), 1884 (Box 37, File 16)
  - Arthur H. Meritt to Laura E. Dean, 1894 (Box 37, File 17)
  - Arthur H. Meritt to Laura E. Dean, 1894 - 1895 (Box 37, File 18)
  - Arthur H. Meritt to Laura E. Dean, 1895 (Box 37, File 19)
  - Arthur H. Meritt to Laura E. Dean, 1895 (Box 37, File 20)
  - Arthur H. Meritt to Laura E. Dean, Undated (Box 37, File 21)
  - C. F. D. Meritt (Elizabeth Kirkland’s mother-in-law) to Laura E. Dean, 1894 - 1895 (Box 37, File 22)
  - C. F. D. Meritt (Elizabeth Kirkland’s mother-in-law) to Laura E. Dean, Undated (Box 37, File 23)
  - C. F. D. Meritt (Elizabeth Kirkland’s mother-in-law) to her Aunt, 1894 - 1895 (Box 37, File 24)
  - C. F. D. Meritt’s Aunt to C. F. D. Meritt (Elizabeth Kirkland’s mother-in-law), 1899 (Box 37, File 25)
  - Recommendation letters for Arthur H. Meritt, 1891 (Box 37, File 26)
  - Telegram to Arthur H. Meritt, Undated (Box 37, File 27)
  - Illegible or unsigned letters (Box 37, File 28)
- Family Materials
  - Greeting cards (Box 37, File 29)
  - Greeting cards (Box 37, File 30)
  - Greeting cards (Box 37, File 31)
  - Greeting cards (Box 37, File 32)
  - Invitations (Box 37, File 33)
  - Invitations (Box 37, File 34)
- Family Materials
  - Invitations (Box 38, File 1)
  - Name Cards (Box 38, File 2)
  - Autograph Book (Miss Mary Henderson), 1879 (Box 38, File 3)
  - Autograph Book (Arthur H. Meritt), 1883 (Box 38, File 4)
  - Address Book (Arthur and Cornelia Meritt) (Box 38, File 5)
  - Address Book (C. T. Dean), 1876 (Box 38, File 6)
  - Advertising Cards (Box 38, File 7)
  - Notebook (Miss Elizabeth Kirkland) (Box 38, File 8)
  - Notebook (Arthur H. Meritt) (Box 38, File 9)
  - Notebook (Arthur H. Meritt) (Box 38, File 10)
  - Photographs (Box 38, File 11)
- Family Materials
  - Certificate (Mary Elizabeth Kirkland) (Box 39, File 1)
  - Academic Career (Elizabeth Kirkland) (Box 39, File 2)
  - Academic Career (B. D. Meritt) (Box 39, File 3)
  - Academic Career (Arthur H. Meritt) (Box 39, File 4)
  - Academic Career (James Kirkland Meritt) (Box 39, File 5)
  - Academic Career (Elizabeth Kirkland Meritt) (Box 39, File 6)
  - Academic Career (Mary Henderson) (Box 39, File 7)
  - Academic Career (Elizabeth Kirkland and Hattie McDaniel) (Box 39, File 8)
  - Children’s Drawings (Box 39, File 9)
  - Programs (Box 39, File 10)
  - Bills and Receipts (Box 39, File 11)
  - Poems (Box 39, File 12)
  - Treatises (Arthur and Cornelia Meritt) (Box 39, File 13)
  - Treatises (Arthur and Cornelia Meritt) (Box 39, File 14)
  - Treatises (Arthur and Cornelia Meritt) (Box 39, File 15)
  - Addresses (by different authors) (Box 39, File 16)
  - Newspaper Clippings (Box 39, File 17)
  - Newspaper Clippings (Box 39, File 18)
  - Newspaper Clippings (Box 39, File 19)
  - Newspaper Clippings (Box 39, File 20)
  - Miscellaneous Materials (Box 39, File 21)
- Additions to Kirkland Papers
  - Writings
    - Essay on Homer, 1882; Prize Exam Paper, 1877; Notebook in German, n.d. (Box 40, File 1)
    - A Study of the Anglo-Saxon Poetry, The Harrowing of Hell, Dissertation for the Acquisition of the Degree of Doctor of Philosophy from the University of Leipzig, 1885, James H. Kirkland (Box 40, File 2)
  - Personal and Biographical
    - Notebook, 1884 - 85, Auszuge aus T. Kolleg - Geschichte der Englischen (Box 40, File 3)
    - Roman Antiquities Notebooks I - III (Box 40, File 4)
    - The Teacher’s Model Pocket Register and Grade Book, 1889 - 1892 (Box 40, File 5)
    - Subscriptions to Rebuilding Fund to May 1908 for James H. Kirkland (Box 40, File 6)
    - Bonds; Ten Year Low Yield Bond Values (Box 40, File 7)
    - Bond Tables - Harris Trust and Savings Bank, 1921; Modern Bond Values, 1935 (Box 40, File 8)
    - Pocket Edition of Monthly Bond Values 1939, Financial Publishing Co.; Memorabilia, Doll (Box 40, File 9)
- Newspaper Clippings
  - 1886 - 1893 (Box 41, File 1)
  - 1895 - 1898 (Box 41, File 2)
  - 1902 (Box 41, File 3)
  - 1903 (Box 41, File 4)
  - 1904 (Box 41, File 5)
  - 1905 (Box 41, File 6)
  - May - June 1906 (Box 41, File 7)
  - August - December 1906 (Box 41, File 8)
  - February - November 1907 (Box 41, File 9)
  - December 1907 (Box 41, File 10)
  - 1908 (Box 41, File 11)
  - March - July 1909 (Box 41, File 12)
  - 1909 (Box 41, File 13)
  - September - October 1909 (Box 41, File 14)
  - November 1909 (Box 41, File 15)
  - December 2 - 19, 1909 (Box 41, File 16)
  - December 26 - 30, 1909 (Box 41, File 17)
  - January 1910 (Box 41, File 18)
  - February - March 1910 (Box 41, File 19)
  - May - June 1910 (Box 41, File 20)
  - July - December 1910 (Box 41, File 21)
  - 1911 (Box 41, File 22)
  - 1912 (Box 41, File 23)
  - January - February 1913 (Box 41, File 24)
  - March - May 1913 (Box 41, File 25)
  - June - November 1913 (Box 41, File 26)
  - 1914 (Box 41, File 27)
  - 1915 (Box 41, File 28)
  - 1919 - 1929 (Box 41, File 29)
  - 1930-1932 (Box 41, File 30)
  - 1933-1935 (Box 41, File 31)
  - 1936 - February 1937 (Box 41, File 32)
  - May 1937 - August 1939 (Box 41, File 33)
  - October 1939 - 1941 (Box 41, File 34)
  - n.d. ( Education - misc.) (Box 41, File 35)
  - n. d. (miscellaneous) (Box 41, File 36)
  - n.d. (poems, humor, iris, etc.) (Box 41, File 37)
  - n.d. ( schools, colleges, education, etc.) (Box 41, File 38)
  - n.d. (V.U. faculty, students, athletics, etc.) (Box 41, File 39)
- Newspaper Clippings
  - n.d. ( Kirkland and offers from other Universities) (Box 42, File 1)
  - The biography of Kirkland by Edwin Mims, published by the Vanderbilt University Press (Box 42, File 2)
  - Kirkland retirement and death, 40 years as Chancellor (Box 42, File 3)
  - Kirkland, Vanderbilt University, misc. (Box 42, File 4)
  - n.d. (Vanderbilt University vs. Church, c. 1905 - 1914) (1) (Box 42, File 5)
  - n.d. (Vanderbilt University vs. Church, c. 1905 - 1914 (2) (Box 42, File 6)
  - n.d. (Vanderbilt University vs. Church c. 1905 - 1914 (3) (Box 42, File 7)
  - n.d. (Vanderbilt University vs. Church c. 1905 - 1914 (4) (Box 42, File 8)
  - n.d. (Vanderbilt University vs. Church c. 1905 - 1914 (5) (Box 42, File 9)
  - n.d. (Vanderbilt University vs. Church c. 1905 - 1914 (6) (Box 42, File 10)
  - n.d. (Vanderbilt - Peabody, c. 1907 - 1910) (1) (Box 42, File 11)
  - n.d. (Vanderbilt - Peabody, c. 1907 - 1910) (2) (Box 42, File 12)
  - n.d. (Vanderbilt - Peabody, c. 1907 - 1910) (3) (Box 42, File 13)
  - n.d. (Vanderbilt - Peabody, c. 1907 - 1910) (4) (Box 42, File 14)
  - n.d. (Vanderbilt - Peabody, c. 1907 - 1910) (5) (Box 42, File 15)
- Envelopes (Box 43)
- Envelopes (Box 44)